Guide to the Asians Against Domestic Abuse Records
University of Houston Libraries
Asians Against Domestic Abuse Records
1985-2010
2001-2010
02/2010-005
Asians Against Domestic Abuse
0.50 linear feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
This collection includes the articles of incorporation, by-laws, administrative documents, informational brochures, records of consciousness raising and fund-raising events, and newspaper clippings for the Asians Against Domestic Abuse organization.
Historical Note:
Asians Against Domestic Abuse (AADA) was founded in 2001 in order to raise awareness about domestic abuse in the Asian community and provide legal advocacy, community education, social service assistance, and interpretation for the Asian American community. The AADA was founded by Swapna Chaunduri, Rehana Sarwar, Salma Siddiqi, and Shantha Raghuthaman, who organized its first Board of directors. AADA works closely with other social services and women’s centers in Texas and is currently still active. For more information see http://www.aadainc.org.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Administrative records; Brochures; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence; Newsletters
Topical Term:
Abused women -- Care -- Texas -- Houston; Asian Americans -- Texas -- Houston; Family violence -- Texas -- Houston; Nonprofit organizations -- Texas -- Houston; Social advocacy -- Texas -- Houston; Social service -- Texas -- Houston; Women -- Services for -- Texas -- Houston
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes the articles of incorporation, by-laws, administrative documents, informational brochures, records of consciousness raising and fund-raising events, and newspaper clippings for the Asians Against Domestic Abuse organization. Materials are arranged topically and then chronologically, whenever possible. The series included are: Administrative Documents and Brochures and Other Publicity. The collection is comprised of 12 folders contained in 1 box.
Detailed List of Contents
- Administrative Documents, id118385
  Scope and Contents
  This series includes the articles of incorporation, by-laws, financial and administrative records of the Asians Against Domestic Abuse organization. The series is arranged topically.
  - Articles of incorporation, 2001; id118388 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Amended bylaws, 2009; id118389 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Board of directors information, undated; id118390 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - AADA Committee descriptions, undated; id118391 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Manuals, policies and procedures, undated; id118392 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Strategic Plan, 2010–2013; id118393 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Administrative forms, undated; id118394 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Non-profit corporation forms, 2006, 2008; id118395 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Insurance forms, 2010, 2011; id118396 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Donations and grants, 2009, 2010; id118397 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Brochures and Other Publicity, id118386
  This series includes informational brochures, records for fundraising and consciousness raising events, and newspaper clippings presenting information about Asians Against Domestic Abuse and its events and activities.
  - Brochures and presentations, undated; id118399 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Events, 2009-2010; id118400 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, 2002-2008; id118401 (Box 1, Folder 13)